=City of Streamer=
=วังวนรักหลังม่านเมืองมายา=
=Episode 15=
=ตอนที่ 15=
Miss Yu,
คุณอวี๋
don't be too upset.
ต้องทำให้ตัวเองอารมณ์แจ่มใสขึ้นมานะคะ
Mr. Jiashang's birthday party is coming.
อีกไม่กี่วันก็จะถึงงานวันเกิดของคุณชายใหญ่แล้
Show up in your best look,
คุณต้องแต่งตัวให้สวยสดงดงาม
and Mr. Yang will feel sorry
จะได้ทำให้คุณหยางที่ช่วงนี้เย็นชาใส่คุณ
for neglecting you.
ตำหนิตัวเองจึงจะถูก
Thank you for cheering me up.
คุณเฝิงปลอบคนเก่งจริง ๆ
Sadly,
น่าเสียดาย
I can only come in an old gown
ฉันก็มีชุดเต้นรำเก่าแค่ชุดเดียว
and pray that no one will laugh at me.
แค่ไม่ให้ทุกคนหัวเราะเยาะฉันก็พอแล้ว
Who will laugh at you?
ใครหัวเราะเยาะใครกันเหรอ
Uncle.
ลุงเขย
There you are, Zhihui.
จือฮุ่ยมาแล้วเหรอ
Long time no see.
ไม่เจอกันพักหนึ่ง
You've grown this tall.
สูงขนาดนี้แล้วเหรอ
Where are my wife and daughters?
พวกคุณนายล่ะ
Ma'am has taken Miss Fanglin and Fanghua to try on the new dresses
คุณนายพาคุณหนูไปลองชุดใหม่ค่ะ
and they won't come back for lunch.
บอกว่าจะไม่กลับมาทานมื้อกลางวันแล้ว
Leave us.
นายไปเถอะ
Who did you say would laugh at you?
เมื่อกี้เธอว่าใครหัวเราะเยาะพวกเธอนะ
I was just joking with Miss Feng.
หนูก็แค่พูดเล่นกับคุณเฝิงน่ะค่ะ
Jiashang's birthday party
หนูพูดว่าอีกไม่กี่วัน
is just a few days away.
ก็ถึงงานเลี้ยงวันเกิดน้องเจียซ่างแล้ว
I'm afraid my shabby dress would disgrace you.
กลัวว่าชุดหนูจะซอมซ่อ ทำคุณลุงขายหน้าเอาน่ะค่ะ
When a girl attends a party,
สาว ๆ ร่วมงานเต้นรำ
how can she not
จะไม่มี
have a beautiful dress?
กระโปรงสวย ๆ ได้ยังไง
It's so thoughtless of your aunt.
เพราะป้าเธอน่ะ
She should have bought a new dress for you, too.
เขาควรจะตัดชุดให้เธอด้วย
I don't mean that, Uncle.
หนูไม่ได้หมายความว่าอย่างนี้นะคะลุงเขย
I was just joking.
หนูก็แค่พูดไปเรื่อยเปื่อย
Aunt has already taken good care of me.
คุณป้าดีกับหนูมากแล้วค่ะ
Shaoqing left many dresses when she ran away.
ตอนที่เส้าชิงไปทิ้งเสื้อผ้าไว้ไม่น้อย
They're supposed to be donated to the church.
เดิมทีจะบริจาคให้โบสถ์คริสต์
Zhihui, if you don't mind,
จือฮุ่ยถ้าเธอไม่รังเกียจ
go pick some.
ก็ไปเลือกสักตัวสองตัว
She doesn't like to dance.
ปกติเขาไม่ชอบเต้นรำ
Many of her dresses are still new.
กระโปรงหลายตัวยังไม่เคยใส่เลย
If any dresses strike your fancy,
ถ้าเธอชอบตัวไหน
take them away.
ก็เอาไปได้เลย
Uncle,
ลุงเขย
would it be all right?
แบบนี้จะดีเหรอคะ
Why would it not?
มีอะไรไม่ดีกัน
I've approved of that.
ลุงก็อนุญาตแล้ว
Remember to come often
ต่อไปต้องจำไว้นะ
and visit us.
มานั่งเล่นที่บ้านบ่อย ๆ
Thank you, Uncle.
ขอบคุณค่ะลุงเขย
Go ahead.
ไปเถอะ
Miss Feng,
คุณเฝิงคะ
could you please go with me?
คุณไปเลือกเป็นเพื่อนฉันหน่อยได้ไหมคะ
Yes.
ได้ค่ะ
Thank you, Uncle.
ขอบคุณค่ะลุงเขย
That's the wardrobe.
ตู้เสื้อผ้าอยู่ทางนั้นค่ะ
These dresses are beautiful!
เสื้อผ้าดี ๆ อย่างนี้
What a pity if they're donated!
บริจาคไปน่าเสียดายแย่
Uncle was so nice to her,
ลุงเขยดีกับเธอขนาดนี้
but she still ran away
แต่ว่าเธอก็หนีไปอยู่ดี
and chose to live a hard life.
ไปรับความลำบากข้างนอก
I don't know what she's thinking.
ไม่รู้จริง ๆ ว่าคิดยังไง
I guess
คุณหนูซุน
Miss Sun loves freedom more.
คงจะรักอิสระมากกว่ามั้งคะ
There's no such thing as absolute freedom.
มีอิสระแน่แท้ที่ไหนกัน
Miss Feng,
คุณเฝิง
how do I look in this dress?
คุณว่าฉันใส่ชุดนี้เป็นยังไงคะ
Good.
สวยดีนะคะ
But I remember
แต่ว่าชุดนี้
Miss Sun often wore this dress.
ฉันจำได้ว่าคุณหนูซุนมักจะใส่บ่อย ๆ
She did?
งั้นเหรอ
It suits me well, I think.
แต่ฉันคิดว่ามันเหมาะกับฉันทีเดียว
It's made in France.
สินค้าจากฝรั่งเศสด้วย
I'd like to pick this.
ตัวนี้แหละ
I'll go try it on.
ฉันไปลองก่อน
We've finally bought everything we need.
คราวนี้ก็ซื้อครบแล้วนะ
Aunt.
คุณป้า
Zhihui.
จือฮุ่ย
What brings you here?
เธอมาได้ยังไง
My mother made some marmalade.
แม่ทำแยมส้มค่ะ
She knows you like it
รู้ว่าคุณป้าชอบทาน
and asked me to bring some to you.
ก็เลยตั้งใจให้หนูเอามาฝาก
Come on. Be seated.
มา ๆ นั่งก่อน
Jiashang's birthday is coming soon.
วันเกิดน้องเจียซ่างใกล้จะถึงแล้ว
But I don't have a good dress
หนูก็ไม่ได้มีชุดกระโปรง
for his birthday party.
อะไรจะใส่ไปงานเลี้ยง
When I was chatting with Miss Feng,
เมื่อกี้คุยอยู่กับคุณเฝิง
Uncle happened to hear us.
ไม่ทันระวังลุงเขยมาได้ยินเข้า
He then asked me to pick
ลุงเขยก็เลยให้หนูไปเลือก
one of Miss Sun's dresses.
ชุดของคุณหนูซุนมาใส่ก่อน
I should have thought of it.
ป้าไม่ถี่ถ้วนเอง
Don't say that.
ไม่หรอกค่ะ
Here.
รับไปสิ
You just bought it.
อันนี้คุณป้าเพิ่งซื้อมา
I can't accept it.
หนูรับไว้ไม่ได้หรอกค่ะ
Now, no one still cares about me,
ตอนนี้ก็มีแค่เธอกับแม่เธอ
but you and your mother.
ที่ใส่ใจป้าแล้วนะ
I want to give it to you.
ป้าจะให้เธอ
Thank you, Aunt.
ขอบคุณค่ะคุณป้า
Men in the Huang family are all unreliable.
ผู้ชายบ้านตระกูลหวงพึ่งพาไม่ได้สักคน
They're just hopeless.
มีแต่ไม่เป็นโล้เป็นพาย
When they think I have no say in the Rong family,
เห็นป้าอยู่ที่บ้านตระกูลหรง ไม่มีสิทธิ์มีเสียงอะไร
they completely ignore me.
ไม่สนใจไยดีป้าเลย
Those snobs.
จริง ๆ เลยนะ
For them,
ป้าอุตส่าห์ทำเพื่อพวกเขา
I even annoyed my husband.
จนทะเลาะกับสามีของตัวเองแล้ว
Aunt,
คุณป้าคะ
don't get angry at such ungrateful men.
อย่าไปโมโหเพราะคนใจดำพวกนั้นเลยนะคะ
Tell me
งั้นบอกป้ามาซิ
what happened between you and Xiucheng.
เธอกับซิ่วเฉิง มันเป็นยังไงกันแน่
All lovebirds sometimes quarrel.
มีคู่รักที่ไหนไม่ทะเลาะกันบ้างล่ะ
If he's still cold to you,
ถ้าเขายังเป็นแบบนี้ต่อไป
don't be afraid.
เธอก็ไม่ต้องกลัวนะ
You know what?
ป้าจะบอกให้
At the dancing party,
วันงานเต้นรำ
there will be many handsome young men.
เต็มไปด้วยหนุ่มหล่อมีความสามารถ
By then,
พอถึงเวลานั้น
I'll pick another good boyfriend for you.
ป้าจะช่วยเธอหาหลานเขยดี ๆ สักคน
Thank you, Aunt.
ขอบคุณค่ะคุณป้า
Don't worry.
เธอไม่ต้องห่วงหรอก
Count on me.
ให้เป็นหน้าที่ของป้า
Aunt, it's getting late.
คุณป้าคะ นี่ก็เย็นแล้ว
I'll take my leave.
หนูกลับก่อนนะคะ
My mother is in poor health.
แม่ไม่ค่อยสบาย
I want to spend more time with her.
หนูอยากอยู่เป็นเพื่อนท่านให้มากหน่อย
Fine.
ก็ดีเหมือนกัน
I won't keep you for dinner, then.
งั้นป้าไม่รั้งเธออยู่กินข้าวเย็นแล้วนะ
See you, cousins.
ไปก่อนนะน้อง ๆ
Be careful on your way back.
เดินทางระวังด้วยนะ
Miss.
คุณหนู
Come on.
มาค่ะ
Be careful.
ระวังนะคะ
Mother, what do you think of this?
แม่ดูสิคะอันนี้เป็นยังไงบ้าง
Look at this.
มา ดูอันนี้
- Ma'am. - It doesn't matter.
คุณนายคะ
Concubine Sun is back with the baby.
คุณนายรองซุนอุ้มลูกกลับมาแล้วค่ะ
Why is she back?
เธอกลับมาได้ยังไง
I don't know.
ไม่ทราบสิคะ
She just gave birth, didn't she?
ยังไม่ออกจากอยู่เดือนหลังคลอดไม่ใช่เหรอ
there you are.
อยู่กันพร้อมเลยนะ
Good evening, Ma'am.
สวัสดีคุณนาย
What are you waiting for?
พวกเธอยืนเหม่ออะไรอยู่ล่ะ
Go get a warmer for me.
ไปตั้งกาน้ำร้อนให้ฉันสิ
It's cold out here.
ด้านนอกลมหนาวแรง
My son is weak
คุณชายน้อยของฉันน่ะ
and he must be warm.
รับความทรมานไม่ไหวหรอกนะ
Go.
ไปสิ
Come, come.
รีบมาเร็ว
Yes.
ค่ะ
Go.
ไปเถอะ
Wait.
รอเดี๋ยว
Get me a cup of hot tea.
เทน้ำชามาให้ฉันแก้วหนึ่งด้วย
Yes, Ma'am.
ค่ะ คุณนาย
Has my room been cleaned?
ทำความสะอาดห้องหรือยัง
All the furniture should be sterilized with alcohol more than three times.
เครื่องใช้ทุกอย่างต้องใช้ แอลกอฮอล์ฆ่าเชื้อสามครั้งขึ้นไป
Come on,
ฉันว่าคุณนายรองซุน
if you really cared for your son,
ถ้าอยากจะให้ดีต่อลูกชายเธอจริง ๆ
you should have stayed in hospital.
ก็ควรจะอยู่ที่โรงพยาบาลต่อ
Doctors and nurses are available there.
หมอพยาบาลก็เรียกได้ตลอดเวลา
The servants assigned to you
คนใช้ที่จวนหรงส่งไป
are also at your service.
เธอก็เรียกใช้ได้ตามใจ
These days,
ตอนนี้ทุกคนกำลัง
we're preparing for Jiashang's birthday party.
เตรียมงานเลี้ยงวันเกิดของคุณชายใหญ่
And we're quite busy.
เดิมทีก็ยุ่งจะตายอยู่แล้ว
But you're suddenly back.
เธอรีบกลับมาตอนนี้
Aren't you making more trouble?
กลับมาทำให้วุ่นวายน่ะสิไม่ว่า
Sorry, Ma'am,
ขอโทษทีนะคะคุณนาย
for the trouble
ฉันกับคุณชายน้อยของฉัน
my son and I have brought you.
ทำให้คุณต้องลำบากแล้ว
Mother...
แม่คะ
Shizhen.
ซื่อเจิน
There you are.
เธออยู่ห้องด้วย
Concubine Sun?
คุณนายรอง
Don't call me that.
เรียกคุณนายรองอะไรกัน
You sound distant.
ฟังดูห่างเหินจะตาย
You...
คุณ
You have left hospital?
คุณออกจากโรงพยาบาลแล้วเหรอคะ
Your brother took good care of me in the hospital.
ที่โรงพยาบาลพี่ชายเธอดูแลฉันดีมาก
Now that you're his sister,
เธอเป็นน้องสาวของเขา
you're my sister, too.
ก็เป็นน้องสาวของฉันด้วย
From this day on,
นับแต่นี้ไป
we'll be sisters.
เราก็เรียกกันเป็นพี่น้อง
Call me Sister Sun.
เธอเรียกฉันว่าพี่ซุนแล้วกันนะ
Sisters?
พี่น้อง
Mr. Jiashang's birthday party will be held tomorrow.
พรุ่งนี้ก็งานเลี้ยงวันเกิดของคุณชายใหญ่แล้ว
Have you prepared a dress for that?
เธอเตรียมชุดราตรีไปถึงไหนแล้ว
I know you haven't.
ฉันว่าแล้วเชียว
Here.
นี่
It's for you.
ให้เธอ
How does it look?
สวยไหม
Take it.
เธอรีบรับไว้เถอะน่า
It's too expensive. I can't accept it.
อันนี้มันมีค่าเกินไปค่ะ ฉันรับไว้ไม่ได้หรอก
It's not expensive.
มีค่าอะไรกันเล่า
I'm regarding you as my sister.
ฉันเห็นเธอเป็นน้องสาวแล้ว
Don't decline the dress.
กระโปรงตัวเดียวเกี่ยงไปเกี่ยงมากับฉันไปได้
Take it.
รีบรับไป
You need jewels for the dress, too.
มีชุดราตรีแล้ว จะขาดเครื่องประดับไม่ได้
Go pick some with me.
ไป ไปเลือกกับฉัน
Master has given me a lot of jewels.
คุณท่านให้อัญมณีฉันเยอะแยะ
Many of them are new.
หลายชิ้นเป็นของใหม่ทั้งนั้นเลย
Take whatever you like.
เธอชอบชิ้นไหนก็เอาไปเลย
Don't feel hesitant.
อย่าได้เกรงใจเชียวนะ
Go.
ไปเถอะ
No, thanks.
ไม่เป็นไรจริง ๆ ค่ะ
I'm grateful for the dress.
แค่นี้ฉันก็รู้สึกขอบคุณมากแล้ว
Well,
งั้นกระโปรงตัวนี้
I'll borrow this dress, then.
ฉันขอยืมใส่ก่อน
After the birthday party,
พอหลังจากงานเลี้ยงแล้ว
I'll wash it and return it to you.
ฉันซักให้สะอาดเอามาคืนคุณ
I don't need any jewels, though.
ส่วนเครื่องประดับไม่ต้องหรอกค่ะ
Fine, then.
ดูเธอสิเกรงใจไปได้
I... I'll leave you alone.
งั้น ฉันไปก่อนนะ
Thank you.
ขอบคุณนะคะ
I happened to find this perfume.
(เจียซ่าง) (บังเอิญเจอ)
I think its aroma suits you very well.
(รู้สึกว่ามันเหมาะกับคุณมาก)
Thank you for your hard work with my birthday party.
(ขอบคุณคุณครูที่เหนื่อยกับงานวันเกิดของผม)
Hope you'll like it.
(หวังว่าคุณจะรับไว้)
Jiashang.
(เจียซ่าง)
All right. Get ready.
โอเค ทุกคนเตรียมตัวนะครับ
Look at the camera.
ทุกคนมองทางผมนะครับ
Here comes my baby son. Come on.
ลูกชายของฉันมาแล้ว
Let Father hold you.
พ่ออุ้มนะ พ่ออุ้ม
Don't cry.
ไม่ร้องนะ
There you are.
มาแล้ว
Here we are.
มาแล้ว ๆ
Come in, please.
เชิญครับ
There you are, sir.
คุณก็มาด้วยเหรอ
It looks nice.
ไม่เลวเลยจริง ๆ
Mr. Zhang, come in, please.
เถ้าแก่จาง เชิญด้านในครับ
This way, please.
เชิญทางนี้ครับ เชิญทางนี้ค่ะ
Come and entertain the guests.
มา ๆ ต้อนรับหน่อย
Take them in.
พาเข้าไปข้างใน
This way.
เชิญทางนี้ค่ะ
Go over there.
เธอไปทางนั้นดีกว่า
All right.
ได้
Come on.
มา
Come in, please.
เชิญด้านในครับ
Welcome.
ยินดีต้อนรับ
- Welcome. Welcome. - Congratulations.
เชิญคุณตามสบายนะคะ
Congratulations.
ยินดีด้วย
- Welcome. Welcome.
ยินดีต้อนรับนะครับ
- Mr. Rong, congratulations. - Welcome.
- เถ้าแก่หรง - ยินดีด้วย ยินดีด้วย
- Mr. Rong, long time no see. - Long time no see.
ไม่เจอกันนานเลยนะ
Don't stand on ceremony.
ไม่ต้องเกรงใจนะคะ เชิญด้านในค่ะ
Come in, please.
พี่
Hi, there.
ไม่เจอกันตั้งนาน
Long time no see.
ไม่เจอนานเลยนะคะ
- Mr. Rong, long time no see. - Come in, please.
เชิญด้านในค่ะ
Congratulations.
ยินดีด้วยนะครับ
Thank you.
ขอบคุณครับ
Welcome. Come in, please.
ยินดีต้อนรับนะครับ เชิญด้านใน
Aunt.
คุณป้า
Looks as if the dress were made for you.
กระโปรงเหมือนตัดมาเพื่อเธอเลยนะ
Thank you, Uncle.
ขอบคุณค่ะลุงเขย
Jiashang, happy birthday.
น้องเจียซ่าง
Thank you, Zhihui. Come in, please.
ขอบคุณครับพี่ เชิญด้านใน
- Congratulations.
ยินดีด้วยครับ
Welcome. Welcome.
ยินดีต้อนรับ
- Come in, please.
- เชิญด้านในค่ะ - เชิญด้านในครับ
Mr. Jiashang is quite handsome.
คุณชายหรงนี่รูปหล่อจริง ๆ นะครับ
He's quite lucky.
ช่างมีวาสนาจริง ๆ นะครับ
Yeah.
นั่นสิครับ
Cheers.
มาครับ
I hear Mr. Jiashang has been back in Shanghai for nearly half a year.
ได้ยินว่าคุณชายหรงกลับมาเซี่ยงไฮ้ได้ครึ่งปี
He looks handsome,
อย่ามองว่าเขาหน้าตาไม่เลว
but he's eccentric
แต่นิสัยแปลกประหลาดทีเดียว
and he's quite gauche.
ไม่ถนัดเข้าสังคม
He speaks English very fluently.
พูดภาษาอังกฤษคล่องปร๋อเชียว
Even when he stands there,
เขาแค่ยืนเฉย ๆ
I can spend the whole day looking at him.
ฉันน่ะมองเขาแบบนี้ได้ทั้งวันเลยนะ
Stop looking. Here comes his girlfriend.
ไม่ต้องมองแล้ว
Uncle, Aunt,
คุณลุงคุณป้า
long time no see.
ไม่เจอนานเลยนะคะ
You look beautiful today.
วันนี้เธอสวยจริง ๆ
You look better, Aunt.
คุณป้าสวยกว่าค่ะ
Greetings, Uncle.
คุณลุง
What a nice dress you're in!
วันนี้เธอแต่งตัวสวยจริง ๆ
Thank you.
ขอบคุณค่ะ
Jiashang, happy birthday.
เจียซ่าง สุขสันต์วันเกิด
- Thank you. - Uncle. Aunt.
ขอบคุณมาก
There you are, Xiucheng.
คุณป้า
Jiashang, happy birthday.
เจียซ่าง แฮปปีเบิร์ธเดย์
Thank you, Xiucheng.
ขอบคุณครับพี่
Help me entertain the guests. Go.
แกไปช่วยดูแลหน่อย ไปเร็ว
- Go ahead. - I'll leave you alone, then.
ไปเถอะ
Xiucheng.
พี่ซิ่วเฉิง
Fanglin, Fanghua.
ฟางหลิน ฟางฮว่า
- Lanxin. - Mm?
พี่หลันซิน
- Hurry.
เร็วเข้า
- Go ahead. Go. - I'm leaving with them, then.
ไปเถอะ ๆ
- Welcome. Welcome. - Long time no see.
ยินดีต้อนรับครับ
- Congratulations. - Hope you'll have a good time.
ยินดีด้วยครับ ๆ
- Happy birthday!
ยินดีด้วยนะคะ
- Come in, please.
เชิญด้านในครับ
- There you go. - Let's get in.
เราเข้าไปข้างในกันครับ
- Happy birthday! - Come in, please.
เชิญด้านในครับ
Welcome.
ยินดีต้อนรับครับ
Come on in.
เชิญครับ
Come in, please.
เชิญด้านในค่ะ ๆ
Welcome.
ยินดีต้อนรับครับ
Congratulations.
ยินดีด้วยนะครับ
Thank you for coming.
ขอบคุณมากครับ
- Long time no see. - Yeah. It's been a long time.
ไม่เจอกันนานเลย
Come in, please.
เชิญด้านในค่ะ
♪Is love obsession♪
♪รักคือความลุ่มหลง♪
♪Or abandon♪
♪หรือการปล่อยวาง♪
♪Destiny makes me fall♪
♪โชคชะตาลากฉันตกลง♪
♪Into the bottomless darkness♪
♪ตกลงสู่ความมืดมิด♪
♪Loving you is my final destiny♪
♪ชะตากรรมของฉัน มีเพียงรักคุณ♪
♪I'm destined to use up my luck to meet you♪
♪ถูกลิขิตให้ใช้โชคทั้งหมด มาพบเจอคุณ♪
♪I'm destined to use all my strength to look for you♪
♪ถูกลิขิตให้ใช้กำลังทั้งหมด เสาะหาคุณ♪
♪I'm destined to spend the rest of my life♪
♪ถูกลิขิตให้ใช้ชีวิตที่เหลือทั้งหมด♪
♪Protecting and accompanying you♪
♪ปกป้องคุณ อยู่เคียงข้างคุณ♪
♪In destiny♪
♪ในชะตาที่ถูกลิขิตมา♪
♪We can't control ourselves♪
♪เราต่างยากจะควบคุมตัวเอง♪
♪I'm destined to use up my luck to meet you♪
♪ถูกลิขิตให้ใช้โชคทั้งหมด มาพบเจอคุณ♪
♪I'm destined to use all my strength to look for you♪
♪ถูกลิขิตให้ใช้กำลังทั้งหมด เสาะหาคุณ♪
♪Our love is destined to last♪
♪ถูกลิขิตให้ความรักของเรายืนยาว♪
Miss Feng.
คุณครูเฝิง
Jiashang,
เจียซ่าง
happy birthday.
แฮปปีเบิร์ธเดย์
Thank you.
ขอบคุณครับ
♪The story won't be over♪
♪เรื่องราวเล่าไม่จบ♪
What's this?
นี่คืออะไรครับ
A sextant?
เครื่องวัดแดด
Navigators in the past
ใช้เครื่องวัดนี้เพื่อหาตำแหน่งทิศทาง
You told me
คุณเคยบอกว่า
that you wanted to be a pilot.
คุณอยากเป็นนักบิน
I think flying a plane
การได้โบยบินบนท้องฟ้า
is like sailing in the sea of clouds.
ก็เท่ากับล่องเรือในทะเลเมฆหมอกใช่ไหม
Jiashang,
เจียซ่าง
I hope one day,
หวังว่าสักวันหนึ่ง
you can bravely chase your dream
คุณจะสามารถตามหาความฝัน ของตัวเองได้อย่างเต็มที่
and be a free and fearless pilot
เป็นนักบินที่อิสระและกล้าหาญ
high up in the sky.
บนท้องฟ้าสีครามอันกว้างใหญ่
Shizhen,
ซื่อเจิน
- I... - Jiashang.
ผมอยาก
Jiashang, let me introduce her to you.
พี่ใหญ่ ฉันขอแนะนำหน่อย
This is Miss Hashimoto
นี่ก็คือคุณหนูฮาชิโมโตะ
Shizhi, this is my brother.
ซือจือ นี่พี่ชายฉันเอง
Jiashang?
อาซ่าง
It's really you.
เป็นเธอจริง ๆ ด้วย
Shizhi?
ซือจือ
You know each other?
พวกพี่รู้จักกันเหรอ
Aren't you Mr. Tang?
เธอแซ่ถังไม่ใช่เหรอ
Why are you Mr. Rong now?
ทำไมกลายมาเป็นพี่ใหญ่ตระกูลหรงได้
Tang? Oh, I see.
ถัง อย่างนี้นี่เอง
When he studied in Chongqing,
ตอนพี่ใหญ่เรียนที่ฉงชิ่ง
Father asked him to use our uncle's family name
คุณพ่อกลัวเขาจะไม่ปลอดภัย
in case he would be in danger.
ก็เลยให้ใช้แซ่ของลุง
Shizhi,
ซือจือ
you and my brother knew each other in Chongqing?
เธอรู้จักกับพี่ใหญ่ตั้งแต่ที่ฉงชิ่งแล้วเหรอ
Do you remember
พวกเธอยังจำ
the young man I told you about
ผู้ชายคนที่ฉันเคยเล่าให้พวกเธอฟัง
who liked to eavesdrop when I played the piano?
ว่าชอบแอบมาฟังฉันเล่นเปียโนได้ไหม
So, that's my brother?
หรือว่าผู้ชายคนนั้นคือพี่ใหญ่
Oh, dear. What a coincidence!
โอ้โห
I'm sorry.
ขอโทษนะ
What I just did
ในสถานที่แบบนี้ ที่ฉันทำไปเมื่อกี้
is quite impolite.
เสียมารยาทมากจริง ๆ
No.
ไม่หรอก
I was just too surprised.
ฉันก็แค่ประหลาดไปหน่อย
Why are you a Japanese girl?
ทำไมเธอถึงเป็นคนญี่ปุ่นได้ล่ะ
My father turns out to be a Japanese merchant.
ที่จริงพ่อฉันเป็นนักธุรกิจชาวญี่ปุ่น
Shortly after you left,
หลังจากเธอไปได้ไม่นาน
he had my little brother and me
พ่อก็ส่งคนมารับฉันกับน้องชายไปที่โตเกียว
and he restored our identities.
คืนสถานะของพวกเรา
I've been trying to look for you,
ฉันอยากจะตามหาเธอมาตลอด
but I don't know where I can find you.
แต่ไม่รู้จะเริ่มหาจากที่ไหน
Jiashang,
อาซ่าง
do you remember
เธอยังจำที่ฉันเคยพูด
what I said when you left?
ตอนที่เธอบอกลาฉันได้ไหม
If we're predestined to meet,
ถ้ามีวาสนา
we will meet again.
พวกเราจะต้องได้พบกันอีกแน่
See? Here we meet again.
เธอดูสิ ฉันพูดถูกจริง ๆ
Looks like you've been living a good life.
เธอดูมีชีวิตที่ดี
Jiashang,
อาซ่าง
I never dreamed
ฉันไม่คิดไม่ฝันเลยว่า
that I could meet you again like this.
จะได้พบเธออีกอย่างนี้
What are you doing here?
ทำไมมารวมกันอยู่ตรงนี้หมดเลยล่ะ
Miss Feng.
คุณครูเฝิง
You look gorgeous.
วันนี้คุณสวยจังเลยค่ะ
I almost didn't recognize you.
จำแทบไม่ได้เลย
Thank you, Miss Du.
ขอบคุณค่ะคุณหนูตู้
You're the most beautiful girl here.
คุณหนูตู้ต่างหากที่สวยที่สุดในงาน
And who is this?
คุณคนนี้คือ
This is Miss Hashimoto from Hashimoto Company.
คุณหนูใหญ่แห่งบริษัทฮาชิโมโตะค่ะ
Nice to meet you.
ยินดีที่ได้พบค่ะ
Jiashang,
เจียซ่าง
my father and brother have come.
พ่อกับพี่ชายฉันมาแล้ว
Go say hello to them.
ไปทักทายสักหน่อยสิ
You don't want me
คุณคงไม่อยากให้ฉันประกาศ
to announce our engagement
เรื่องการหมั้นของเรา
to your new girl and ex-girlfriend on such an occasion, do you?
ต่อคนรักเก่าและใหม่ของคุณหรอกนะ
Excuse me.
ขอตัวก่อนนะ
Miss Du looks gorgeous.
คุณหนูตู้คนนี้สวยจังเลย
Who's she?
ไม่ทราบว่าเขาคือ
She's the second daughter of the owner of Fumin Bank.
คุณหนูรองแห่งธนาคารฟู่หมิน
But he has never told me about her.
เมื่อก่อนไม่เคยได้ยินอาซ่างพูดถึง
Did he get to know her after he was back in Shanghai?
อาซ่างกลับเซี่ยงไฮ้มาแล้วถึงรู้จักกันเหรอ
Shixun.
พี่
What are you looking at?
มองอะไรอยู่น่ะ
I'm looking for you.
ฉันกำลังหาพี่อยู่พอดี
When did you come?
มาตั้งแต่เมื่อไร
Before you came downstairs.
ก่อนที่เธอจะลงมา
Your new dress?
ซื้อชุดกระโปรงมาใหม่เหรอ
Concubine Sun gave it to me.
คุณนายรองให้ฉันน่ะ
You know what?
พี่รู้ไหม
Since she left hospital,
หลังจากเธอออกจากโรงพยาบาล
she has greatly changed
มีท่าทีต่อฉัน
her attitude towards me.
พลิกกลับไปร้อยแปดสิบองศาเลยทีเดียว
Sometimes, she's just too enthusiastic.
บางครั้งกระตือรือร้นจนฉันตั้งรับไม่ค่อยทันเลย
I'm quite curious.
ฉันยังคิดอยู่เลย
What on earth did you do to her?
นี่พี่เอายาวิเศษอะไรให้เธอกินกันแน่
Doctors care for patients.
คุณธรรมของผู้เป็นหมอ
She's just a patient of mine.
เธอก็เป็นแค่คนไข้ของพี่เท่านั้นแหละ
Shixun,
พี่
do you remember
พี่ยังจำได้ไหมตอนเด็ก ๆ
we listened to the radio next door
พวกเราเต้นรำกันในสวน
and danced in our yard when we were little?
โดยฟังเสียงวิทยุของบ้านข้าง ๆ
When I make enough money,
รอให้พี่หาเงินได้แล้ว
I'll buy you the most beautiful dress
จะตัดชุดราตรีที่สวยที่สุดให้เธอ
so that you no longer need to borrow it from anyone else.
ต่อไปพวกเราไม่ต้องยืมคนอื่นอีกแล้ว
Thank you.
ขอบคุณนะพี่
What are you staring at?
ดูอะไรน่ะจดจ่อขนาดนั้น
Nothing.
ไม่มีอะไร
I'm just checking
ฉันก็แค่อยากจะดู
whom the Rong family has dealings with.
ว่ามีใครบ้างที่ไปมาหาสู่กับตระกูลหรง
I hear
มีคนบอกว่า
that Rong Dingkun
ช่วงนี้หรงติ้งคุน
has been very thick with the Japanese.
สนิทสนมกับชาวญี่ปุ่น
The Japanese are quite ambitious.
ชาวญี่ปุ่นนี่ก็มีความทะเยอทะยานไม่น้อย
Recently,
ช่วงนี้
they've played many more tricks in the Northeast.
มีความเคลื่อนไหวเล็ก ๆ ที่ตะวันออกเฉียงเหนือมากขึ้นเรื่อย ๆ
When Rong Dingkun cooperates with them,
สองฝ่ายนี้มาอยู่ร่วมกันได้
they're quite birds of the same feather
ก็ไม่ต่างกันเลยจริง ๆ
and partners in crime.
เหมือนสัตว์ร้ายร่วมมือกัน
You said
พี่พูดแบบนี้
exactly the same thing as Rong Jiashang said.
เหมือนกับที่หรงเจียซ่างพูดเป๊ะเลย
That's how he described his family?
คุณชายหรงพูดถึงบ้านตัวเองแบบนี้เหรอ
Don't tease me.
อย่ามาล้อเล่นหน่อยเลย
- Excuse me. - No problem.
ขอตัวสักครู่นะครับ
Everybody. Everybody.
ทุกท่าน ทุกท่าน
This way, please.
มาค่ะ เชิญค่ะ
Here comes Mr. Meng
เถ้าแก่เมิ่ง
from Yongli Bank.
แห่งธนาคารหย่งลี่มาอวยพร
What's going on?
อะไรกันเนี่ย
The chairman of Yongli Bank
ประธานของธนาคารหย่งลี่
came to the birthday of Mr. Jiashang?
มาอวยพรวันเกิดให้คุณชายหรงเหรอ
Yongli Bank?
ธนาคารหย่งลี่
You don't even know it?
ธนาคารหย่งลี่เธอก็ไม่รู้จักเหรอ
that has suddenly got popular.
เป็นธนาคารเอกชนที่จู่ ๆ ก็ดังขึ้นมา
It's said to be supported by foreigners
ได้ยินว่ามีภูมิหลังจากต่างประเทศ
and it's financially strong.
มีศักยภาพมหาศาลจริง ๆ
That's right.
นั่นสินั่นสิ
I'd like to see
ฉันล่ะอยากจะเห็น
the expression on Rong Dingkun's face
สีหน้าของหรงติ้งคุน
when he meets me again.
ตอนที่ฉันได้เจอกับเขาอีกครั้ง
You know him?
รู้จักเหรอ
No way.
จะเป็นไปได้ยังไง
Mr. Rong,
เถ้าแก่หรง
how have you been lately?
ไม่เจอกันนานสบายดีนะครับ
I'm sorry.
ขอโทษด้วยนะครับ
I interrupted you.
ผมมาขัดจังหวะคุณแล้ว
Please go on.
เชิญคุณต่อเลย
You didn't.
ที่ไหนกันล่ะ
It is always a pleasure
สหายมาหาจากแดนไกล
to see an old friend.
จะไม่ยินดีได้อย่างไร
Xu'an,
น้องซวี่อัน
shall we
ประเดี๋ยว
talk later?
พวกเราค่อยรำลึกความหลังกัน
Somebody.
มา
Get some wine to Mr. Meng.
เสิร์ฟเหล้าให้คุณชายเจ็ดตระกูลเมิ่ง
Thank you.
ขอบคุณครับ
I'm sure
คนคนนี้กับตระกูลหรง
this man doesn't get along with the Rong family.
ความสัมพันธ์ไม่ค่อยดีแน่ ๆ
Actually, it's worse.
(ไม่เพียงแค่ไม่ดี)
There's a blood feud between them.
(สองตระกูลนี้เคียดแค้นกันฝังลึกเลยต่างหาก)
Thank you.
ขอขอบคุณ
Thank you, everybody, for coming to my son's birthday party.
ขอบคุณทุกท่านที่มาร่วม งานฉลองวันเกิดของลูกชายผม
When my son was 18 years old,
ตอนที่ลูกชายผมอายุครบสิบแปดปี
he was still in the Military Academy
ยังเรียนหนังสืออยู่ที่โรงเรียน
so that he didn't have a party.
ไม่อาจจัดงานใหญ่ได้
Today,
วันนี้
I'm holding the party for him
จึงได้ถือโอกาสที่เขาอายุครบยี่สิบปี
when he's 20 years old.
มาชดเชย
Like all the other parents,
ความคาดหวัง
I always have simple expectations
ที่พ่อแม่ทุกคนมีต่อลูก ๆ
for my children.
มักเรียบง่ายเสมอ
I want my son to be
หวังว่าอนาคตเขาจะกลายเป็นคนที่
a decent man
ซื่อสัตย์ตรงไปตรงมา
who will love his family
กตัญญูมีเมตตา
and will win honor
สร้างความภาคภูมิใจ
for his clan
ให้ครอบครัว
and his nation.
ให้ประเทศชาติ
Thank you.
ขอบคุณครับ
Thank you, everybody.
ขอบคุณทุกท่านครับ
Come on, Jiashang.
มาเถอะ เจียซ่าง
Thank you, seniors,
ขอบคุณผู้ใหญ่ทุกท่าน
for taking care of me.
ที่ให้การดูแลในวันที่ผ่านมา
And thank you for coming, my friends.
ขอบคุณมิตรสหายที่มาในวันนี้
Today is my birthday.
วันนี้เป็นวันเกิดของผมหรงเจียซ่าง
Hope you'll have a good time
ขอให้ทุกท่านฉลองอย่างมีความสุข
and enjoy yourselves.
ฉลองอย่างสนุกสนานครับ
- Happy birthday! - Bravo!
สุขสันต์วันเกิด
Come on.
มาเถอะ
I didn't expect Miss Hashimoto
นึกไม่ถึงเลยว่าคุณหนูฮาชิโมโตะ
to be Jiashang's girlfriend in Chongqing.
จะเป็นแฟนที่ฉงชิ่งของพี่ใหญ่
When I first knew it,
ตอนเริ่มแรก
I thought it was their destiny.
ก็รู้สึกว่าวาสนานำพาดีจนพูดไม่ออก
But think about it.
แต่พอคิด ๆ ดูแล้ว
Lanxin is here, too.
งานวันนี้พี่หลันซินก็อยู่ด้วย
New girlfriend and the ex-girlfriend...
คนรักใหม่มาเจอคนรักเก่า
How awkward it is!
บรรยากาศน่าอึดอัดมากเลย
Yeah.
นั่นสิ
Miss Hashimoto looks at Jiashang
สายตาที่เขามองพี่ใหญ่
as if she still loves him.
เหมือนยังมีเยื่อใย
Have we caused trouble for Jiashang?
นี่พวกเราหาเรื่องลำบาก ให้พี่ใหญ่แล้วหรือเปล่า
We...
มันก็
But,
งั้น
she is already here.
แต่เขาก็มาแล้ว
We can't just expel her.
จะไล่เขากลับไปก็ไม่ได้หรอก
Besides, we're hosts of the party.
อีกอย่างวันนี้เราสองคน เป็นเจ้าบ้านรับแขกนะ
We have to take care of her,
จะยังไงก็ต้องดูแลเขาให้ดี
or we'll be too impolite.
จะเสียมารยาทไม่ได้
Ms. Chen.
ป้าเฉิน
Mr. Jiashang.
คุณชายใหญ่
Where's my father?
พ่อฉันล่ะ
He has gone to the study on the second floor with Mr. Meng.
คุณท่านกับเถ้าแก่เมิ่ง ไปที่ห้องหนังสือชั้นสองค่ะ
Tell me.
ฉันถามป้าหน่อย
Ma'am looked very unhappy
ตอนที่คุณนายเห็นเถ้าแก่เมิ่ง
when she saw Mr. Meng.
สีหน้าไม่ยินดีเอาซะเลย
There must be a reason for that.
ต้องมีที่มาที่ไปอะไรแน่ ๆ
You've been serving her for the longest time.
ป้ารับใช้คุณนายมานานที่สุด
You know the reason, don't you?
ป้าน่าจะรู้ใช่ไหม
Mr. Jiashang,
คุณชายใหญ่คะ
I'm a mere maid.
ฉันก็เป็นแค่คนใช้
I don't know much about Ma'am.
เรื่องของคุณนายฉันไม่ทราบหรอกค่ะ
Just tell me.
ป้าบอกฉันมาเถอะ
I won't tell anyone else.
ฉันไม่พูดออกไปหรอก
Actually,
ที่จริง
it happened a dozen years ago.
นั่นเป็นเรื่องเมื่อสิบกว่าปีมาแล้ว
Ma'am was pregnant with Mr. Jiaxin.
ตอนนั้นคุณนายกำลังตั้งท้องคุณชายรอง
But Master got to know a Miss Meng
คุณท่านกลับไปรู้จักกับผู้หญิงคนหนึ่ง
in the painting club.
ก็คือคุณเมิ่งที่สมาคมภาพเขียน
For Miss Meng,
เพื่อคุณเมิ่งคนนี้
Master wasn't back home for months.
คุณท่านไม่กลับบ้านเป็นเดือน ๆ
Though pregnant,
คุณนายอุ้มท้องโต
Ma'am talked to Miss Meng.
ไปเจรจากับคุณเมิ่ง
Miss Meng was stubborn.
คุณเมิ่งกลับ
Instead of leaving Master,
ไม่เพียงไม่ไปจากคุณท่าน
she said
ยังจะบอกว่า
she objected to arranged marriage
ต่อต้านการคลุมถุงชน
and wanted free love.
ต้องการความรักที่อิสระ
Ma'am was pissed off.
ทำเอาคุณนายโกรธมากเลย
Besides, Master had a problem
ประกอบกับตอนนั้นคุณท่าน
with his business at that time.
ทำธุรกิจเกิดข้อผิดพลาดขึ้นนิดหน่อย
Ma'am nearly had a miscarriage.
คุณนายเกือบจะแท้ง
Later, Concubine Wang was pregnant
ต่อมาก็คุณนายรองใหญ่ตั้งท้อง
so that Miss Meng left in a fit of anger.
ถึงได้ทำให้คุณเมิ่งนั่นโกรธจนหนีไป
Mr. Meng up there
เถ้าแก่เมิ่งที่ชั้นบนนั่น
is Miss Meng's younger brother.
ก็คือน้องชายของคุณเมิ่ง
So, it's about love affairs.
ที่แท้ก็หนี้รักนี่เอง
Mr. Jiashang, if you don't mind,
ถ้าคุณชายใหญ่ไม่มีเรื่องอะไรแล้ว
I'm getting back to work.
ฉันไปทำงานก่อนนะคะ
Go ahead.
ไปเถอะ
Bro.
เพื่อน
I'm sorry.
ขอโทษนะ
I'm late.
มาช้า
Here's your birthday present.
นี่ของขวัญวันเกิดนาย
Check it out.
ลองเปิดดูสิ
Thank you, bro.
ขอบคุณมากนะเพื่อน
It looks exquisite.
ประณีตมากเลย
Do you like it?
ชอบไหม
Thank you.
ขอบใจนะ
Mr. Rong.
เถ้าแก่หรง
Don't stand there. Be seated.
อย่ายืนอยู่เลยครับ นั่งเถอะ
This is your home
ที่นี่คือบ้านคุณ
and over a hundred guests are out there.
ด้านนอกก็มีแขกอยู่ร่วมร้อยคน
I can't hurt you.
ผมทำอะไรคุณไม่ได้หรอก
Xu'an,
น้องซวี่อัน
you've really astonished me.
นายทำให้ฉันทึ่งไปเลย
I heard you came back.
ก่อนหน้านี้ได้ยินว่านายกลับมาแล้ว
I thought you were back for some small businesses.
ก็นึกว่านายกลับมาทำธุรกิจเล็ก ๆ
Unexpectedly,
นึกไม่ถึงจริง ๆ
you're the chairman of Yongli Bank.
ว่านายคือประธานธนาคารหย่งลี่
You keep quite a low profile.
ปิดบังไว้ลึกทีเดียว
My family isn't as glorious as before.
ถึงแม้ตระกูลเมิ่งจะไม่ได้รุ่งโรจน์เหมือนเมื่อก่อน
But a sleeping lion
แต่อูฐที่ผอมตาย
is still stronger than a barking dog.
ก็ตัวใหญ่กว่าม้าอยู่ดี
With the support of my family,
ตอนนี้ผมอาศัยการสนับสนุนจากทางบ้าน
I'm doing some business.
ทำธุรกิจนิด ๆ หน่อย ๆ
I haven't made many achievements.
ก็ไม่ถือว่าประสบความสำเร็จอะไร
I'm just not disgracing
อย่างมากก็แค่ถือได้ว่า
my ancestors.
ไม่ทำให้บรรพบุรุษต้องขายหน้าแหละครับ
Over the years,
หลายปีมานี้
I've been thinking of you
ฉันมักจะนึกถึงนาย
and your sister.
นึกถึงพี่สาวนายอยู่บ่อย ๆ
Qingzhi...
ชิงจือ
Is she all right?
เธอสบายดีไหม
She's dead.
พี่สาวผมตายแล้ว
How come?
จะเป็นไปได้ยังไง
You look so surprised.
เถ้าแก่หรงแปลกใจขนาดนี้เลยเหรอ
If you really cared for her,
ถ้าเถ้าแก่หรงเป็นห่วงพี่ผมจริง ๆ
you would have asked about her
ก็คงไปสืบข่าวของเธอแล้ว
and you wouldn't be so surprised.
คงไม่ต้องถึงกับทำสีหน้าเช่นตอนนี้
When did she die?
ตั้งแต่เมื่อไร
After my family moved to America,
หลังจากพวกเราย้ายไปอเมริกา
she fell ill.
เธอก็ล้มป่วย
After over half a year's treatment,
อดทนยื้อเวลาได้ครึ่งค่อนปี
she still passed away.
แต่ก็ไม่ไหวอยู่ดี
But don't worry.
แต่คุณไม่ต้องเป็นห่วง
She died peacefully
เธอไปอย่างสงบ
and never mentioned even a single word
ไม่ได้พูดถึงเรื่องคุณ
about you.
อีกเลยแม้แต่คำเดียว
She died so early.
มาด่วนจากไปขนาดนี้
Where is she buried?
ฝังอยู่ที่ไหน
In San Francisco.
ซานฟรานซิสโก
I really didn't expect this.
นึกไม่ถึงจริง ๆ
She was so young.
เธอยังอายุน้อยอยู่เลย
After she got married in America,
ฉันนึกมาตลอดว่าเธอแต่งไปที่อเมริกา
I thought she would live a happy life
มีชีวิตที่ดี
and even her children would grow up.
ตอนนี้เกรงว่าลูกก็คงโตแล้ว
What about you?
แล้วนายล่ะ
Are you
ตอนนี้
focusing on the bank only?
ก็ตั้งใจทำธนาคารแล้วเหรอ
My family
ตระกูลเมิ่ง
does small businesses.
เดิมทีกิจการก็เล็ก
And I've hired capable assistants.
ทั้งยังจ้างคนที่มีความสามารถมาทำงาน
I have nothing to worry about.
ไม่ต้องให้ผมกังวลอะไร
But at present,
เพียงแต่ตอนนี้
the situation isn't stable.
สถานการณ์ไม่ค่อยมั่นคง
Bank lending is dangerous
ทำธนาคารปล่อยกู้ยังไงก็ค่อนข้างอันตราย
and quite risky.
และมีความเสี่ยงสูงมาก
It's influenced by the wars, too.
ทั้งยังได้รับผลกระทบจากสงครามอีกด้วย
Any carelessness
ถ้าไม่ระวังเพียงนิดเดียว
will make me go bankrupt.
ก็จะสิ้นเนื้อประดาตัวได้
But you're different, Mr. Rong.
ไม่เหมือนเถ้าแก่หรง
With great fortunes,
เดี๋ยวนี้ต่างจากเมื่อก่อน
you're no longer what you were.
รุ่งโรจน์ราวแสงอาทิตย์ยามกลางวัน
When there's a chance, I'd like to learn from you.
หากมีโอกาสคงต้องมาขอคำปรึกษาจากคุณสักหน่อย
You flatter me, Xu'an.
น้องซวี่อันชมเกินไปแล้ว
Young men like you are promising
คนหนุ่มอย่างพวกนายต่างหากที่เป็นคลื่นลูกใหม่
and you will rule the future.
เจ้าแห่งอนาคต
I'm so old
คนแก่ ๆ อย่างฉัน
that I've fallen behind the times.
ล้าสมัยตั้งนานแล้ว
It's modest of you, Mr. Rong.
เถ้าแก่หรงถ่อมตัวแล้ว
I remember your residence
ผมจำได้ว่าจวนตระกูลหรงในสมัยนั้น
wasn't as splendid as it is now.
ยังไม่โอ่อ่าเท่านี้
But now,
ตอนนี้
it's magnificent.
รุ่งโรจน์เรืองรองจริง ๆ
Xu'an,
น้องซวี่อัน
I'm sorry for your sister.
ฉันรู้สึกผิดต่อพี่สาวนาย
She loved me wholeheartedly,
ตอนนั้นเธอจริงใจต่อฉัน
but I failed to love her like that.
แต่ฉันกลับไม่อาจตอบแทนมิตรภาพของเธอ
Over the years,
หลายปีมานี้ฉัน
I've never stopped thinking of her.
ไม่มีวันไหนที่ฉันไม่คิดถึงเธอ
But I wasn't brave enough
แต่ฉันก็ไม่มีความกล้า
to ask about her.
จะไปสืบข่าวคราวของเธอ
I didn't expect her to die so early.
นึกไม่ถึงจริง ๆ ว่าเธอจะอายุสั้นเช่นนี้
You weren't brave enough?
ไม่มีความกล้าเหรอ
Come on.
พอเถอะครับ
When you tricked
ตอนนั้นที่เถ้าแก่หรง
my sister
หลอกล่อให้พี่สาวผม
into smoking opium,
สูบฝิ่น
you were quite brave.
มีความกล้าหาญมากเลยนะครับ
Blessed by ancestors,
ตระกูลเมิ่ง
my family
ได้รับการคุ้มครองจากบรรพบุรุษ
barely survived.
ลมหายใจเฮือกสุดท้าย
I exhausted all efforts
ผมเองก็ทุ่มเทสุดความสามารถ
to have revived
ถึงได้ค่อย ๆ
my family properties.
ชุบชีวิตกิจการของตระกูลขึ้นมาได้
I'm thinking...
แต่ผมก็คิดอีกว่า
Actually, money isn't important.
ที่จริงเงินทองล้วนเป็นของนอกกาย
But my family heirloom can't be in the hand of anyone else.
แต่สมบัติปกปักของบ้าน จะพลัดไปอยู่ข้างนอกไม่ได้
Mr. Rong, I'd like to ask you.
ผมอยากถามเถ้าแก่หรงสักหน่อย
You swindled my sister
กิเลนทองคำที่คุณ
of the Gold Kylin.
หลอกเอาไปจากมือของพี่สาวผม
Where is it now?
ตอนนี้อยู่ที่ไหนเหรอครับ
I knew you came back for it.
ฉันเดาไว้แล้วว่านายกลับมาเพราะเรื่องนี้
Believe it or not,
พูดไปแล้วนายอาจจะไม่เชื่อ
over the years,
หลายปีมาแล้ว
I've been looking for the Gold Kylin, too.
ฉันก็คอยหาข่าวคราวกิเลนทองคำนั่นอยู่เสมอ
When I was in trouble,
ตอนที่ฉันตกอยู่ในสถานการณ์ลำบาก
your sister gave it to me.
พี่สาวนายมอบมันให้ฉัน
I sold it to pay my debt.
ให้ฉันขายไปใช้หนี้
The Gold Kylin
กิเลนทองคำตัวนั้น
carries the love between Qingzhi and me.
บรรจุไว้ซึ่งมิตรภาพของฉันกับชิงจือ
Since my condition got better,
ตั้งแต่สถานการณ์ฉันดีขึ้น
I've been trying to get it back.
ก็ตั้งใจ
You're quite good at finding excuses.
เถ้าแก่หรงนี่แต่งเรื่องเก่งจริง ๆ
My sister told me
พี่สาวผมบอกกับผมเองเลยว่า
that you swindled her of it.
ถูกคุณหลอกเอาไป
Forget it.
ช่างเถอะ ช่างเถอะ
It's been so many years.
ยังไงเรื่องมันก็ผ่านไปตั้งนานแล้ว
There's no point in arguing.
เถียงกันเรื่องนี้ก็ไม่มีความหมายอะไร
But Mr. Rong,
แต่ก็ยังต้องขอให้เถ้าแก่หรง
please return the Gold Kylin to me.
เอากิเลนทองคำคืนให้ตระกูลเมิ่ง
I will, of course.
นั่นมันแน่นอนอยู่แล้ว
Tomorrow,
พรุ่งนี้ฉัน
I'll send more men
จะส่งคนไปจัดการ
to look for the treasure.
หาสมบัติล้ำค่านี้กลับมาให้ได้
I'm afraid you don't understand my determination.
ดูท่าเถ้าแก่หรงจะยังไม่ค่อยเข้าใจเจตนาของผม
If you think I'm joking,
ถ้าคุณคิดว่าผมกำลังล้อเล่นละก็
you're wrong.
งั้นคุณคิดผิดแล้ว
I don't think so.
จะเป็นไปได้ยังไง
Twenty years ago, a mother and her children
ยี่สิบปีก่อนมีแม่ลูกสามคน
ran into some bandits
ตอนที่กำลังผ่านไปตำบลไป่หลิว
when they passed Bailiu Town
เจอโจรกลุ่มหนึ่ง
and they were murdered.
รุมฆ่าอย่างทารุณ
Do you remember?
คุณยังจำได้ไหม
It suddenly occurs to me
จู่ ๆ ผมก็คิดว่า
that if your eldest son were still alive,
ถ้าลูกชายคนโตของเถ้าแก่หรงยังมีชีวิตอยู่ละก็
he would be as handsome and talented
น่าจะเหมือนกับเจียซ่าง
as Rong Jiashang.
สง่าผ่าเผยหน้าตาหล่อเหลา
Xu'an,
น้องซวี่อัน
I don't understand what you're talking about.
ทำไมฉันถึงไม่เข้าใจว่านายกำลังพูดอะไร
You just don't want to admit it.
เพราะเถ้าแก่หรงยังไม่อยากยอมรับน่ะสิ
That's right.
ก็จริง
Over the years,
หลายปีมานี้
nearly all your relatives in your hometown
ญาติ ๆ จากบ้านเกิดของตระกูลหรง
have been dead.
ตายไปเหลือแค่ไม่กี่คน
Even your servants
ต่อให้เป็นคนใช้
have been replaced several times.
ก็เปลี่ยนไปกลุ่มแล้วกลุ่มเล่า
I guess even your existing wife
แม้แต่คุณนายหรงคนปัจจุบัน
doesn't know
ก็คงไม่รู้
that you had a wife before.
ว่าคุณเคยแต่งงานมีภรรยามาก่อน
She's dead, anyway.
อย่างไรซะคนก็ตายไปแล้ว
She won't stand in your way.
ไม่มีอะไรมาขัดขวางแล้ว
But what if someone knows
กลัวก็แต่จะมีคนรู้
that you killed your first wife
ว่าเพื่อที่จะแต่งงานกับ
and her two children
นางถังจากครอบครัวผู้มีการศึกษาคนนั้น
simply because you wanted to marry Miss Tang
คุณฆ่าภรรยาที่ร่วมทุกข์ร่วมสุขกันมา
who was from a literary family?
และลูกชายลูกสาวด้วยมือตัวเอง
Meng Xu'an,
เมิ่งซวี่อัน
don't sling mud at me.
คุณจะมาพูดใส่ร้ายคนอื่นไม่ได้นะ
I'm not a good man.
ถึงผม หรงติ้งคุนจะไม่ใช่คนดีอะไร
But I would never
แต่เรื่องฆ่าภรรยาฆ่าลูก
kill my wife or children.
ผมทำไม่ได้แน่นอน
Dog doesn't eat dog.
พยัคฆ์ร้ายก็ไม่กินลูกตัวเอง
Why would I hurt my own children?
ผมจะทำร้ายลูก ๆ ตัวเองได้ยังไง
You know very well if you did that.
จะจริงจะเท็จในใจคุณรู้ดีที่สุด
All right.
เอาล่ะ
I'm done here.
ผมพูดจบแล้ว
As for what you would like to do,
เถ้าแก่หรงจะทำยังไงต่อไป
make your own decision.
ก็โปรดพิจารณาเอาเอง
Rong Dingkun.
หรงติ้งคุน
You're a famous philanthropist
ผู้ใจบุญและนักกิจกรรม ทางสังคมแห่งหาดเซี่ยงไฮ้
If people know you're such a devil,
ถ้าคนอื่นรู้ว่าคุณเป็นสารเลวแบบนี้้
what will they think of you?
คุณว่าพวกเขาจะคิดยังไง
Meng Xu'an,
เมิ่งซวี่อัน
you can't accuse me without evidence.
พูดจาไร้หลักฐานนี่
I've been doing business in Shanghai for so many years.
ผมหรงติ้งคุนทำธุรกิจอยู่เซี่ยงไฮ้มาตั้งนาน
You can't overthrow me just as you wish.
ก็ไม่ได้จะยอมให้คนอื่นรังแกได้ตามใจ
Considering my temper,
คุณคิดว่าด้วยนิสัยของผมแล้ว
do you think I would come and meet personally
ถ้าไม่มีหลักฐานเป็นชิ้นเป็นอัน
without conclusive evidence?
ผมจะมาหาคุณด้วยตัวเองเหรอ
You made a good point.
พูดได้ดีจริง ๆ
Dog doesn't eat dog.
พยัคฆ์ร้ายไม่กินลูกตัวเอง
By then, you'll know
ไม่นานเถ้าแก่หรงก็จะรู้ว่า
you can't vindicate yourself
คราบสกปรกบนตัวไม่ใช่ฆ่าปิดปากแล้ว
simply by killing all witnesses.
ก็สามารถชะล้างให้สะอาดได้
Who would be intimate friends
คนที่ฆ่าลูกฆ่าเมีย
with someone that killed his wife and children?
คุณว่าจะมีใครยอมคบหา
And who
จะมีใครยินดี
would be his relatives by marriage?
แต่งงานเกี่ยวดองเป็นญาติด้วยบ้าง
People do dangerous business
ที่ทำธุรกิจเสี่ยงเป็นเสี่ยงตาย
because they want to make money for their wives and children
ไม่ใช่เพื่อจะหาเงินเลี้ยงลูกเมีย
so that they can live a good life.
ให้พวกเขาได้อยู่สบายหรอกเหรอ
But such a ruthless man like you
แต่ความอำมหิตของเถ้าแก่หรงนี้
is one of a kind through the ages.
นับตั้งแต่โบราณมา เรียกได้ว่ามีเพียงหนึ่งเดียว
You came to avenge your sister?
นายมาเพื่อแก้แค้นให้พี่สาวของนาย
♪The aftertaste of love lingers♪
♪ลิ้มรสชาติที่หลงเหลือของเศษรัก♪
♪Hatred snaps roses in two♪
♪ความชังกลับทิ่มแทงกุหลาบ♪
♪Tear-like drizzle seems fine♪
♪น้ำตาที่กลบเกลื่อนเป็นฝนพรำช่างสวยงาม♪
♪Where's the key to one's heart♪
♪ไร้กุญแจไม่อาจไขความในใจ♪
♪Who knows what lies ahead♪
♪ใครจะรู้หนทางข้างหน้า♪
♪The moon isn't lonelier than us♪
♪ดวงจันทร์ไม่อ้างว้างเท่าคนเรา♪
♪Sitting alone to see begonias in the breeze♪
♪นั่งเพียงลำพังคอยสายลมต้นไห่ถังผลิดอกสีแดง♪
♪I still remember our dance♪
♪เต้นรำพร้อมคุณมีสิ่งระลึกถึงด้วยกัน♪
♪The autumn wind can't whisk away thick leaves♪
♪สายลมฤดูใบไม้ร่วง มิอาจพัดพากองใบไม้ที่โรยรา♪
♪I remember the way you smiled at me♪
♪ในความทรงจำ จะคงไว้ซึ่งความจริงจากรอยยิ้มคุณ♪
♪The autumn wind can't whisk away innocent leaves♪
♪สายลมฤดูใบไม้ร่วง มิอาจพัดพากองใบไม้ที่บริสุทธิ์♪
♪However time streams♪
♪ใจคนคือเมืองขนาดเล็ก ท่ามกลางกาลเวลาที่ล่วงเลย♪
♪And trust each other completely♪
♪ชีวิตนี้ ไร้ข้อสงสัยต่อกัน♪
♪However time flies♪
♪กาลเวลาได้คัดกรองพวกเรา♪
♪We're destined to love♪
♪ก็คือคนที่ลิขิตมาให้รัก♪
♪And cherish each other♪
♪คนที่หวงแหน♪